# Khawaja Abdullah

Doha, QR +974 30418876 abdullah\_b2k@outlook.com

## Cyber Security and Information Security Professional

abdullahkhawaja.com github.com/hax3xploit medium.com/@hax.3xploit

Cybersecurity and Information Security Professional with expertise in vulnerability assessment and penetration testing. My experience in the field has equipped me with the knowledge and skills necessary to identify and mitigate cyber risks. I am committed to ensuring the safety and security of organizations and individuals alike. I also possess:

- Experience in scripting languages including Python and Bash.
- Excellent task management. Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously.
- Experience with security tool-kits such as Kali Linux, Nessus, Acunetix, and Burp Suite Pro.
- Proficient in translating information from technical to executive/management terminology.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Python, Bash, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, AWS, Git, Docker, Penetration Testing, Linux/Unix Administration, Web Development, Powershell, Cybersecurity Documentation, OSINT, R&D of Cybersecurity Proof of Concepts.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Recon-tainer

 A docker container that enumerates sub-domains and then filters out XSS, SQLi, SSRF, and more injection point parameters and scans for some low-hanging vulnerabilities automatically.

#### **EZ Tmux**

• Tmux configuration, that supercharges your tmux to build cozy and cool terminal environment which makes tmux very easy to use. It has the ability to send keystrokes into the shells automatically.

#### JOB EXPERIENCE

June 2022 — Present Sr. Red Team Operator Ministry Of Interior Doha, Qatar

- Simulate real-world cyber attacks to identify vulnerabilities.
- Perform penetration testing on applications, networks, and infrastructure.
- Develop attack scenarios to test detection and response.
- Collaborate with security teams to enhance defense strategies.
- Document findings and create detailed reports for stakeholders.
- Stay updated on the latest cyber threats and tools.
- Research, evaluate, document, and discuss findings with IT teams and management.
- Provide security recommendations to mitigate identified risks.

### Sr. Information Security Engineer

NETSOL Technologies Ltd.

Nov 2022 — May 2024

- · Vulnerability assessment and penetration testing.
- Engagement Administrator for SOC 2 Type II audit.
- · Assets management, Vulnerability management, Incident management, and Patch management.
- Monitor security logs and alerts generated by QRadar to identify potential security incidents.
- Worked on IBM QRadar, a SIEM solution, to configure, fine-tune, and optimize log management and security information event management.
- Analyze and investigate security events, determining their impact and appropriate response.
- · Create new testing methods to identify vulnerabilities.
- Search for weaknesses in common software, web applications, and proprietary systems.
- Worked on cloud security, implementing and maintaining security controls and best practices in cloud environments.
- Performed Automation scanning and analysis on the applications on a monthly basis.
- Research, evaluate, document, and discuss findings with IT teams and management.
- Stay updated on the latest malware and security threats.

Lahore, Pakistan

**Cybersecurity Engineer** Oct 2020 — April 2022

Bridge Zones Inc.

- Perform web application, mobile application, and network penetration tests
- Develop processes and implement tools and techniques to perform ongoing security assessments of the environment
- Analyze security test results, draw conclusions from results and develop targeted testing as deemed necessary
- Providing technical consultation on Security Tools and Technical Controls
- + Development of 'rules of engagement' with partners
- Develop security standards, policies, automation scripts
- Perform security reviews of application designs and source code review

**Penetration Tester** June 2018 — August 2020 Islamabad, Pakistan

Hassan Solutions SMC PVT LTD.

- Performed manual application security testing on the everyday changes carried out in the application.
- Generate tools for breaking into security systems.
- Uncovered high vulnerabilities at the infrastructure level for internet-facing websites.
- Documented information security guidance in step-by-step operational procedures.
- Performed static code reviews with the help of automation tools.
- Network scanned using tools like NMap and Nessus.
- Initiative to streamline the access control mechanism of various applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor in Computer Science, SZABIST, Islamabad

2017 — July 2021

Islamabad, Pakistan

Course Highlights:

- · Operating Systems.
- Database Systems.
- Computer Architecture.
- · Computer Networks.
- Algorithms.
- Data Structures.
- Web Technologies.

#### **INDUSTRY CERTIFICATIONS**

- Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP)
- Certified Ethical Hacker Practical (C|EH)
- eLearnSecurity Web Application Penetration Tester (eWPT)
- eLearnSecurity Junior Penetration Tester (eJPT)









#### **AWARDS & HONORS**

- 1st Place DeconstruCT.F 2021
- 2nd RunnerUp Pakistan's First Digital Cybersecurity Hackathon 2021
- CVE Holder CVE-2022-48077 CVE-2021-41643 CVE-2021-41644 CVE-2021-41645 CVE-2021-41646
- Badge of Honor moment.me (2014)
- Hall of Fame getpocket.com (2014)
- Hall of Fame BASF
- Hall of Fame Rozee.pk
- · Hall of Fame United Nations